Thomas Donnelly Papers
Thomas Donnelly Papers
1921-1954
Donnelly, Thomas, 1893-
1 linear ft.
Papers of the American painter. Collection includes correspondence (1924-1932); exhibition announcements and catalogs; photographs; and printed material, including articles by and about Donnelly, clippings, and scrapbooks (1923-1942).
148946
Biographical History
Artist Thomas Donnelly was born in 1893. He was a member of the Art Students League of New York, later retaining a position on the Board. He was an early contributor to the Whitney Club and one of the first to the Whitney Museum of American Art. Several of his paintings form part of the Whitney's permanent collection.
His work was exhibited at the Brooklyn Museum, Carnegie Institute, Corcoran Gallery of Art, Art Institute of Chicago, New York Museum of Modern Art, and many others. He also exhibited at the 19th International Art Exhibition in Venice and at the 1939 World's Fair in New York.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Thomas Donnelly Papers consist of biographical material, correspondence, subject files, and published material.
Biographical material contains a list of Donnelly's exhibitions from 1923 to 1950. Correspondence, incoming, consists of several letters to Donnelly. Subject files contains announcements of showings, publications of the Art Students' League, exhibition catalogs and admission cards, photographs of the artist and his work. Published material includes books about the Whitney Museum, a magazine article by Donnelly, magazine articles about his work, newspaper clippings and scrapbooks of clippings, studio announcements, exhibition catalogs and miscellanea.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name; the other three series are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Donnelly, Thomas, 1893-; Art, American -- 20th century.; Painters -- United States.; Painting, American -- 20th century..; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Exhibition catalogs.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Artists.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - List of exhibitions, 1923-1950 (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - F, 1931 (Box 1)
    - M, S, 1924; 1932 (Box 1)
- Subject files
  - Announcements, 1931-1933; undated (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets, 1921-1922; 1925-1926; Art Students' League of New York (Box 1)
  - Photographs of Donnelly, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Photographs of Donnelly's work, 1935-1944; undated (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Books about Whitney Museum, 1949; 1954,; undated (Box 1)
  - Magazine articles by Donnelly, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Magazine articles about Donnelly (reproductions), 1938; undated (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings about Donnelly, 1944; 1946,; 1950 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks
    - 1923-1931 (Box 1)
    - 1931-1934 (Box 2)
    - 1935-1936 (Box 2)
    - 1938-1942 (Box 2)